this that might be easier is to
think about it in terms of being
half-arsed and I read an article by
somebody who had decided that he wanted
to be a published author and he
did something very clever that I
wouldn't have thought of and very
brave you approached a publisher but
that rather than trying to approach
them with a book he said can I read
your
unsolicited submissions so that's
what's called the slush pile and so he
did that, he read all of the
unsolicited submissions that a publisher
got for a year.
And he said, what he realised from
reading those books was that a lot of
the books, it wasn't that they
weren't the right length, it was just
that they weren't ready. They were,
they were kind of, they weren't
half-arsed, they were
like a tenth of an arse.
And kind of one of the things that
I've started to realise about kind of
like my own work is, you know,
like, when it's, when it's
not, when it's not finished,
there are lots and lots of different
things or kind of different levels
of finishedness, like kind of like
the language, like kind of the logic
of the ideas,
kind of like, you know, kind of the
way that it echoes with other things
that are going on in the book.
So there's kind of like the small
structures, the big structures, the
broader structures, all of that kind
of stuff is going on. And when you
write a first draft, none of that is
right. But it's important to
understand that in a first draft, then
there is something
you've created something you've done
something and that is a good thing
that's a thing that is not shitty
and then everything else yeah okay it
may be a tenth of an arse and then
what you have to do the work that you
have to do then is to improve it to
make it so it's less than a tenth of
an arse until it's a whole arse what
would Freud say I don't know but
anyway that's the kind of idea